A Guide to the The Photographic Archive of Fairfax County, Virginia - The Slide Collection, 1961-1998
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The The Photographic Archive of Fairfax County, Virginia - The Slide Collection, 1961-1998
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 00-00
2.5 linear feet
The Photographic Archive of Fairfax County, Virginia - The Slide Collection consists of 2.5 linear feet of 2,660 color and black and white photographic slides spanning the years 1961-1998.
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection assembled over a 50-year period from donations by various photographers including private individuals and county agencies.
Historical and Biographical Information
In the mid-1950s, Mary K. McCulloch, Director of Fairfax County Public Library (FCPL), established the Virginiana Collection. Ever since then, individuals, authors, private organizations, and public agencies have donated photographs, negatives, slides, postcards, and copies of prints to what is now known as the Virginia Room located in the City of Fairfax Regional Library. The photographic archive grew after 1965 with the establishment of the Fairfax County Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission (later renamed the Fairfax County History Commission) when they continuously donated hundreds of images. The now defunct History Program of the Fairfax County Office of Comprehensive Planning also contributed photographs from their inventory of historic sites and preservation programs.
By the late 1970s, the number of images in the photographic archive reached into the thousands, making retrieval extremely difficult. In response to this problem, the Fairfax County History Commission funded a project of organizing, inventorying, and classifying the collection. Upon completion in 1981, the History Commission published the book Catalog of the Photographic Archive of Fairfax County, Virginia.
At the time, the archive’s slide collection consisted of approximately 1,500 35- millimeter color and black and white slides. Virginia Room librarian Karen Ann Moore compiled an index of the slide collection for the History Commission’s published catalog, however it remained incomplete until the creation of this finding aid in 2021. There are 2,660 slides in this collection which depict historic buildings, documents, events, and many other visual aspects of the county’s history.
Scope and Content
The Photographic Archive of Fairfax County, Virginia - The Slide Collection consists of 2.5 linear feet of 2,660 color and black and white photographic slides spanning the years 1961-1998. Subjects consist of homes, churches, people, events, building exteriors and interiors, documents, portraits, and landscapes significant to Fairfax County’s history. The collection is the result of donations by various photographers, both private individuals and county departments, although very few have been identified.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
The Photographic Archive of Fairfax County, Virginia - The General Collection
None
Index Terms
Fairfax County (Va.); Fairfax County (Va.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Fairfax County (Va.) -- History.; Virginia -- Fairfax County.
Container List
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-1
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-2
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-3
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-4
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-5
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-6
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-7
- Andrew Chapel, 1968 June; Box 1: ANDR-8
- I-495 under construction near Annandale, c. 1959 (photo by Charles Baptie), Undated; Box 1: ANNA-INT-1
- Approaching Annandale, VA from the West, at 236-I-495 Interchange (photo by Nan Netherton), Undated; Box 1: ANNA-INT-2
- Annandale Methodist Church, c. 1870, c. 1976; Box 1: ANNA-METH-1
- Black bear, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-BEAR-1 (1 of 2)
- Black Bear, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-BEAR-1 (2 of 2)
- Tiger Swallowtail on Thistle, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-BUT-1 (1 of 2)
- Tiger Swallowtail on Thistle, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-BUT-1 (2 of 2)
- Eastern Chipmunk, Shenandoah National Park, c. 1970; Box 1: ANIM-CHIP-1
- Virginia White-Tailed Deer, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-DEER-1
- Fawn of Virginia Whitetail Deer, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-DEER-2
- Egret, Mason Neck, c. 1975; Box 1: ANIM-EGR-1 (1 of 3)
- Egret, Mason Neck, c. 1975; Box 1: ANIM-EGR-1 (2 of 3)
- Egret, Mason Neck, c. 1975; Box 1: ANIM-EGR-1 (3 of 3)
- Young Woodchuck, Ground Hog, or Whistle Pig, Shenandoah National Park, c. 1970; Box 1: ANIM-GROU-1 (1 of 2)
- Young Woodchuck, Ground Hog, or Whistle Pig, Shenandoah National Park, c. 1970; Box 1: ANIM-GROU-1 (2 of 2)
- Ponies on Chincoteague Island, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-PONY
- Young Raccoon on a Stump, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-RAC-1
- Animals, Skunk, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-SK
- Wild Turkeys, Shenandoah National Park, Undated; Box 1: ANIM-TURK-1
- Unidentified house, 1968 May; Box 1: ARCH-1
- Arrowhead found near Accotink, Undated; Box 1: ARRO-1 (1 OF 2)
- Arrowhead found near Accotink, Undated; Box 1: ARRO-1 (2 OF 2)
- Mr. Bob Becker at Aspen Grove, 1976; Box 1: ASPE-2
- Ayre House, Chantilly (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1967; Box 1: AYRE-1 (1 of 2)
- Ayre House, Chantilly (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1967; Box 1: AYRE-1 (2 of 2)
- Ayre House, Chantilly (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1967; Box 1: AYRE-1 (3 of 3)
- Belmont/Cocke-Washington House, Lorton, VA, 1968 May; Box 1: BELM-1
- Belmont/Cocke-Washington House, Lorton, VA, 1968 May; Box 1: BELM-2
- Belmont/Cocke-Washington House, Lorton, VA, 1968 May; Box 1: BELM-3
- Belmont/Cocke-Washington House, Lorton, VA, 1968 May; Box 1: BELM-4
- Belmont/Cocke-Washington House, Lorton, VA, 1968 May; Box 1: BELM-5
- Belvoir (sketch), Undated; Box 1: BELV-1
- Bicksler Family Cemetery, Bicksler Farm, Seneca Road and Brockman Lane (photo by Richard Little), 1976 May 5; Box 1: BICK-CEM-1
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: BIEN-1
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: BIEN-2
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: BIEN-3
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, snow scene, Undated; Box 1: BIEN-4
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, interior, Undated; Box 1: BIEN-5
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, interior, empire wreaths, Undated; Box 1: BIEN-6
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, interior, Christmas decorations, Undated; Box 1: BIEN-7
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, interior, Undated; Box 1: BIEN-8
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, upper window nurses quarters, 1971 May; Box 1: BIEN-9
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, side door, 1971 May; Box 1: BIEN-10
- Bienvenue, McLean, VA, front door, 1971 May; Box 1: BIEN-11
- Braddock Road near Olde Forge Estates, flowering trees near Olley Lane, 1974 May; Box 1: BRAD-3 (1 of 3)
- Braddock Road near Olde Forge Estates, flowering trees near Olley Lane, 1974 May; Box 1: BRAD-3 (2 of 3)
- Braddock Road near Olde Forge Estates, flowering trees near Olley Lane, 1974 May; Box 1: BRAD-3 (3 of 3)
- Browns Chapel, prior to relocation (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1967; Box 1: BROW-1 (1 of 2)
- Browns Chapel, prior to relocation (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1967; Box 1: BROW-1 (2 of 2)
- Brown's Chapel, 1968 May; Box 1: BROW-4
- Brown's Chapel, 1968 May; Box 1: BROW-5
- Brown's Chapel, 1968 May; Box 1: BROW-6
- Brown's Chapel, 1968 May; Box 1: BROW-7
- Brown's Chapel, 1968 May; Box 1: BROW-8
- Brown's Chapel, 1968 May; Box 1: BROW-9
- Bull Run Stone Bridge, 1968 March; Box 1: BULL-1
- Bull Run Stone Bridge, 1968 March; Box 1: BULL-2
- Bull Run Stone Bridge, snow scene (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: BULL-4 (1 of 3)
- Bull Run Stone Bridge, snow scene (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: BULL-4 (2 of 3)
- Bull Run Stone Bridge, snow scene (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: BULL-4 (3 of 3)
- Cabell's Mill, Centreville, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1972; Box 1: CABE-1 (1 of 2)
- Cabell's Mill, Centreville, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1972; Box 1: CABE-1 (2 of 2)
- Cabell's Mill, Centreville, VA, 1968 March; Box 1: CABE-2
- Cabell's Mill, Centreville, VA, 1968 March; Box 1: CABE-3
- Cabell's Mill, Centreville, VA, 1968 March; Box 1: CABE-4
- Cabell's Mill, Millers House, Centreville, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: CABE-MH-1 (1 of 3)
- Cabell's Mill, Millers House, Centreville, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: CABE-MH-1 (2 of 3)
- Cabell's Mill, Millers House, Centreville, VA (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: CABE-MH-1 (3 of 3)
- Calvary Christian Church (Church of the Good Shepherd), Burke, VA, 1968 June; Box 1: CALV-1
- Calvary Christian Church (Church of the Good Shepherd), Burke, VA, 1968 June; Box 1: CALV-2
- Calvary Christian Church (Church of the Good Shepherd), Burke, VA, 1968 June; Box 1: CALV-3
- Calvary Christian Church (Church of the Good Shepherd), Burke, VA, 1968 June; Box 1: CALV-4
- Calvary Christian Church (Church of the Good Shepherd), Burke, VA, 1968 June; Box 1: CALV-5
- Calvary Christian Church (Church of the Good Shepherd), Burke, VA, 1968 June; Box 1: CALV-6
- Calvary Christian Church (Church of the Good Shepherd), Burke, VA, 1968 June; Box 1: CALV-7
- Camp Alger, Merrifield, VA, July 1898, Watercolor (Artist: Milton H. Bancroft), Undated; Box 1: CAMP-ALGE-1
- Camp Alger, Merrifield, VA, July 1898, Watercolor (Artist: Milton H. Bancroft), Undated; Box 1: CAMP-ALGE-2
- Carlby, Capt. Carl and Beatrice Porter, Genevieve Marvin in the middle, 1966; Box 1: CARL-1
- Carlby, Capt, Carl Porter installing shingles on garden house, Undated; Box 1: CARL-2
- Centreville District Farm (unidentified), 1970; Box 1: CENT-1
- Centreville Methodist Church (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: CENT-MC-1 (1 of 4)
- Centreville Methodist Church (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: CENT-MC-1 (2 of 4)
- Centreville Methodist Church (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: CENT-MC-1 (3 of 4)
- Centreville Methodist Church (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: CENT-MC-1 (4 of 4)
- Centreville Methodist Church, rear view, 1966 August; Box 1: CENT-MC-2 (1 of 2)
- Centreville Methodist Church, rear view, 1966 August; Box 1: CENT-MC-2 (2 of 2)
- Civil War trenches, Annandale, 5100 Block, Philip Road (photo by Nan Netherton), 1973 April; Box 1: CIVI-1
- Civil War trenches, Annandale, 5100 Block, Philip Road (photo by Nan Netherton), 1973 April; Box 1: CIVI-2
- Harper's Weekly, "Mosby's Guerrillas Destroying Sutlers Train", 5 September 1863 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-3
- "Brilliant Exploit of Company B, Second Calvary, In The Rescue Of Two Of Their Comrades, Who Were To Be Hung By The Confederates At Fairfax, VA." (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-4
- Journal of Alfred Ely, A Prisoner of War in Richmond", Title Page, Undated; Box 1: CIVI-5
- "Journal of Alfred Ely, A Prisoner of War in Richmond", Page mentioning Fairfax Courthouse, Undated; Box 1: CIVI-6
- "Journal of Alfred Ely, A Prisoner of War in Richmond", Page mentioning Fairfax Courthouse, Undated; Box 1: CIVI-7
- "Journal of Alfred Ely, A Prisoner of War in Richmond", Page mentioning Fairfax Courthouse, Undated; Box 1: CIVI-8
- "Journal of Alfred Ely, A Prisoner of War in Richmond", Page mentioning Centreville, Undated; Box 1: CIVI-9
- Newspaper recounting The Battle of Dranesville, 11 January 1862, Undated; Box 1: CIVI-10
- "A Band That Had Seen Service, Near Fairfax, 1863", Undated; Box 1: CIVI-11
- Map showing Fort Marcy and Fort Ethan Allen, Undated; Box 1: CIVI-12
- New York fireman Zouaves turning out to support pickets between Alexandria and Fairfax, 22 June 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-1
- Attack on pickets of Garibaldi Guard, 20 July 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-2
- Washington guarded by U.S. Artillery by Long Bridge, 20 July 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-3
- Bull Run - Engagement between 71st New York and Alabama Regiment, 31 August 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-4
- Stampede from Bull Run, 17 August 1861 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-5
- Two views: Attack on Confederate battery at Bull Run by 27th and 14th N.Y. Regiments, 17 August 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-6
- Attack on Confederate battery at Bull Run, 17 Aug. 1861, 27th and 14th N.Y. Regiments (sketch - detail of CIVI-ILN-6), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-7
- Texas Rangers reconnoitering between Alexandria and Fairfax, 14 September 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-8
- Great Falls of the Potomac, 28 September 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-9
- Yorktown, VA from the Old Nelson House, 5 October 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-10
- Munson Hill with Confederate earthworks, 5 October 1861 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-11
- Bridge across Potomac above Georgetown (Chain Bridge), Looking toward Viginia shore and Patterson's Mill, 12 October 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-12
- Bringing in the Federal wounded after skirmish at Lewinsville, VA.\, 12 October 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-13
- Confederate deserter coming into Federal lines at Munson's Hill, 19 October 1861 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-14
- Three views - October 26, 1861, 1. Franklin's Brigade and Arlington Mill, 2. Confederate Works at Munson Hill, 3. McClellan occupying Confederate positions at Munson Hill, 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-15
- Franklin's Brigade passing Arlington Mill, 26 October 1861 (sketch - detail of CIVI-ILN-15), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-16
- Confederate works on Munson Hill, 26 October 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-17
- McClellan occupying Confederate positions at Munson Hill, 26 October 1861 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-18
- Fairfax Courthouse, Headquarters of Gen. Beauregard, 16 November 1861 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-19
- Advance post of Gen. Blankers' Division surprised at Annandale, VA, 16 January 1862 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-20
- Advance post of Gen. Blanker's Division surprised at Annandale, VA, 18 January 1862 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-21
- Skirmish at Dranesville, VA, 25 January 1862 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-22
- Federals advancing on abandoned Confederate position at Centreville, 12 April 1862 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-23
- Railway Bridge over rapids of James River, 31 May 1862 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-24
- General view of Richmond, VA, 31 May 1862 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-25
- City Quay, Richmond, VA, 31 May 1862 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-26
- Richmond, VA, High Street, 26 July 1862 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-27
- Map of Fredericksburg, 17 January 1863 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-28
- Battle of Fredericksburg: Assault of Federals on Marye's Hill and battery of the Washington Artillery, 31 January 1863 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-29
- Bombardment of Fredericksburg, VA by the Federals, 31 January 1863 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-30
- Gen. Stonewall Jackson, 14 February 1863 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-32
- Warrenton, VA, 30 May 1863 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-33
- Kershaw and Fitzhugh Lee's Division of the Confederate Army, 22 October 1864 (sketch), 1972 October; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-34
- Ruins of the Railway Bridge, Richmond, 15 July 1865 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-35
- Ruins of the Carbine Factory, Richmond, 15 July 1865 (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-36
- Harper's Ferry (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-37
- Harper's Ferry (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-38
- James River (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-39
- Map of Richmond (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-40
- Petersburg, VA (sketch), Undated; Box 1: CIVI-ILN-41
- Clifton, Chapel Road, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Chapel Road, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Chapel Street (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-2
- Clifton, Chapel Street extended (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-3 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Chapel Street extended (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-3 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Chapel Street (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-4 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Chapel Street (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-4 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, VA, c. 1972; Box 1: CLIF-CHAP-5
- Clifton, Ford House, Ford Lane (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-FORD-H-1
- Clifton, Ford Lane (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-FORD-L-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Ford Lane, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-FORD-L-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, General Stores, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-GENL-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, General Stores, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-GENL-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Hetzel House, Pendleton Avenue and Chapel Road (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-HETZ-1
- Clifton, Hetzel House, 1972; Box 1: CLIF-HETZ-2
- Clifton, Hetzel House, 1972; Box 1: CLIF-HETZ-3
- Clifton Hotel, Main Street (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-HO-1
- Clifton Hotel (photo by FCPA), c. 1975; Box 1: CLIF-HO-2
- Clifton, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-2 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-2 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-3 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-3 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-4 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-4 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-5 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-5 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street and Chapel Street (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-6 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Main Street and Chapel Street (photo by J.L. Finglass), 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-MAIN-6 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Meeting House/School, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-MEET-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, Meeting House/School, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-MEET-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Pink House, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-PINK-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Pink House, Main Street, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-PINK-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton Presbyterian Church, Richards Lane, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-PC-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton Presbyterian Church, Richards Lane, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-PC-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton Primitive Baptist Church, Chestnut Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-PRIM-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton Primitive Baptist Church, Chestnut Street, 1974 March; Box 1: CLIF-PRIM-1 (2 of 2)
- Clifton, Quigg House, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-QUIGG-1
- Clifton, School Street, Edge of Prop. Historic District, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-SCH-1 (1 of 2)
- Clifton, School Street, Edge of Prop. Historic District, Undated; Box 1: CLIF-SCH-1 (2 of 2)
- Colvin Run Mill, 1965 January; Box 1: COLV-M-2
- Colvin Run Mill, before restoration (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1965; Box 1: COLV-M-3 (1 of 2)
- Colvin Run Mill, before restoration (photo by E. Breitenbach), c. 1965; Box 1: COLV-M-3 (2 of 2)
- Colvin Run Mill, 1965 January; Box 1: COLV-M-4
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 June; Box 1: COLV-M-5
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-6
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-7
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-8
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-9
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-10
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-12
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-13
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-14
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 June; Box 1: COLV-M-15
- Colvin Run Mill, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-16
- Colvin Run Mill, Restoration (photo by Nan Netherton), 1972; Box 1: COLV-M-17
- Colvin Run Mill, Dedication (photo by Nan Netherton), 1972 July; Box 1: COLV-M-18 (1 of 2)
- Colvin Run Mill, Dedication (photo by Nan Netherton), 1972 July; Box 1: COLV-M-18 (2 of 2)
- Colvin Run Mill, Dedication Ceremony, in costume - Ross Netherton, R. Phillips, William Hoofnagle, Bayard Evans, 1972 July; Box 1: COLV-M-19
- Colvin Run Mill, Water Wheel (photo by FCPA), 1974 May; Box 1: COLV-M-20
- Colvin Run Mill, Works (photo by FCPA), 1974 May; Box 1: COLV-M-21
- Colvin Run Mill, Interior (photo by FCPA), 1974 May; Box 1: COLV-M-22
- Colvin Run Mill, Undated; Box 1: COLV-M-23
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1965 January; Box 1: COLV-M-H-1
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1965 January; Box 1: COLV-M-H-2
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1965 January; Box 1: COLV-M-H-3
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: COLV-M-H-4 (1 of 2)
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: COLV-M-H-4 (2 of 2)
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-5
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1965 January; Box 1: COLV-M-H-6
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-7
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-8
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-9
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-10
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-11
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-12
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 February; Box 1: COLV-M-H-13
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 June; Box 1: COLV-M-H-14
- Colvin Run Mill, Miller's House, 1968 June; Box 1: COLV-M-H-15
- Difficult Run in flood, Old Mill Dam, 1962; Box 1: DIFF-1 (1 of 2)
- Difficult Run in flood, Old Mill Dam, 1962; Box 1: DIFF-1 (2 of 2)
- Old bridge abutment in Difficult Run, N.E. of present Route 7 (photo by Nan Netherton), 1976 August; Box 1: DIFF-2
- Old bridge abutment in Difficult Run, N.E. of present Route 7, Andrew Wolf in foreground (photo by Nan Netherton), 1976 August; Box 1: DIFF-3
- Woods near crossing of Difficult Run, north of Route 7 (photo by Nan Netherton), 1976 August; Box 1: DIFF-4
- Near the site of Shepherds' Ordinary and Wiley's Tavern (photo by Nan Netherton), 1976 August; Box 1: DIFF-5
- Bridge abutment in Difficult Run, N.E. of present Route 7 (photo by Nan Netherton), 1976 August; Box 1: DIFF-6
- Dower House (photo by E. Breitenbach), Undated; Box 1: DOWE-1
- Dranesville, Scott's Run as it enters the Potomac River, Dranesville District Park, Stubblefield Falls, 1975; Box 1: DRAN-1 (1 of 2)
- Dranesville, Scott's Run as it enters the Potomac River, Dranesville District Park, Stubblefield Falls, 1975; Box 1: DRAN-1 (2 of 2)
- Widening Route 193, Dranesville - Moving day! [unidentified house being moved], 1972 March; Box 1: DRAN-H-1
- Widening Route 193, Dranesville - Moving day! [unidentified house being moved], 1972 March; Box 1: DRAN-H-2
- Dranesville Methodist Church (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: DRAN-MC-1
- Dranesville Methodist Church (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: DRAN-MC-2
- Dranesville Methodist Church, 1968 March; Box 1: DRAN-MC-3
- Dranesville Methodist Church, 1968 March; Box 1: DRAN-MC-4
- Dranesville Methodist Church, 1968 March; Box 1: DRAN-MC-5
- Dranesville Methodist Church, 1968 March; Box 1: DRAN-MC-6
- Dranesville Methodist Church (photo by E. Breitenbach), 1967; Box 1: DRAN-MC-7
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-1
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-2
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-3
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-4
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-5
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-6
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-7
- Dranesville Tavern, aerial view, 1968 February; Box 1: DRAN-T-8